1996-0929 Krishna Puja, Camp Vacamas, New York, USA
1996-0929 Krishna Puja, Camp Vacamas, New York, USA
Shri Mataji: Wa wa wa.
Shri Mataji: Wa wa wa.
Wa wa wa. Now. (Hindi)
Wa wa wa. Ora. (Hindi)
We are all sitting like a family sitting together.
Siamo tutti seduti qui insieme come una famiglia.
There should be a show there, eh?... Done very well.
Dovrebbe esserci uno spettacolo lì, vero? Eseguito molto bene.
They’re from Vienna? …
Loro sono di Vienna?
A composition which you yourself have made it into dance - … wa wa.
Una composizione che hai trasposto in danza da sola … Wa wa.
Bring her to Cabella. Yogi: Yes. Yogini: Yes, Shri Mataji.
Portatela a Cabella”. Uno yogi: Sì. Una yogini: Sì, Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji: Wa wa wa. Such a dancer, she is a teacher also.
Shri Mataji: Wa wa wa, che danzatrice, è anche un’insegnante.
I’ll take your leave, and I’ll try to come to tomorrow’s program also]
Mi congederò da voi e cercherò di intervenire anche al programma di domani]
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
Today we have decided to have Krishna Puja
Oggi abbiamo deciso di celebrare un puja a Krishna
because America is the Krishna bhoomi.
perché l’America è la terra (Bhumi) di Krishna.
It’s very surprising that such a great incarnation of Shri Krishna
È molto sorprendente che questa straordinaria incarnazione di Shri Krishna
came even much later than Rama and has sent His special people to live in America.
sia arrivata molto tempo dopo Rama
Of course, there are many who are seeking in this country, no doubt.
Naturalmente numerosi sono i ricercatori in questo paese, è indubbio.
But there are many who are also misleading them.
Ma ci sono anche molte persone che li stanno sviando.
That’s how you find, despite all our effort, we have not been able
Per questo troviamo che, nonostante tutti i nostri sforzi, non siamo riusciti
to expand Sahaja Yoga very much.
ad espandere molto Sahaja Yoga.
What one has to learn from His life is very, very important.
È molto, molto importante ciò che si deve apprendere dalla Sua vita.
The first and foremost thing He taught was collectivity.
La prima cosa, e la più importante,
He used to get hold of small boys
Avvicinava dei ragazzini
and play with them together.
per giocare insieme a loro -
Rama didn't do that.
Rama questo non lo faceva -
He used to get hold of ladies
avvicinava le donne
who were selling milk and also butter,
che vendevano il latte ed il burro
those who used to go to fill their waters - water in the pitcher.
e quelle che andavano a riempire d’acqua le loro brocche.
He is the one who collected all such people in the village of Gokul.
Fu Lui che radunò tutte queste persone nel villaggio di Gokul.
He played all kinds of pranks on His friends
Faceva scherzi di ogni genere ai Suoi amici,
and His mother and the mother’s friends.
a Sua madre ed agli amici di Sua madre.
Behaved just like a very naughty child,
Si comportava proprio come un bambino molto dispettoso
ust to show that He was just like all of us.
solo per mostrare che era proprio come tutti noi.
As you know, He was the incarnation of Shri Vishnu.
Come sapete, Egli era l’incarnazione di Shri Vishnu.
First Shri Rama was born, took incarnation as Shri Rama,
Prima nacque come Shri Rama, si incarnò come Shri Rama
which was in the Aryan race, means that time we had
che era di razza ariana. A quel tempo avevamo
an Aryan race which was sort of superior, superior race than others.
una razza ariana che era in qualche modo superiore, una razza superiore alle altre.
But when He came as Krishna, He took His birth
Ma quando venne come Krishna
They were not superior, they were selling milk, having cowherds
Loro non erano di ceto superiore, vendevano latte, possedevano mandrie
and doing work not of any religious style.
e non svolgevano alcun lavoro di tipo religioso.
But they were innocent simple people living in the villages,
Ma erano persone semplici ed innocenti che vivevano nei villaggi
and they saw the great miracles of Shri Krishna’s childhood.
e videro i grandi miracoli dell’ infanzia di Shri Krishna.
He killed demons. He killed Pootana.
Egli uccise i demoni. Uccise Putana.
All these people were sent by His uncle Kamsa to kill him.
Tutti questi individui erano stati inviati da Suo zio Kamsa per ucciderlo.
It was to be, because He had to prove that He was the incarnation
Doveva andare così perché Egli doveva provare di essere l’incarnazione
of Shri Vishnu and He did it.
di Shri Vishnu, e lo fece.
As a child, how He killed those people is remarkable.
È notevole come, da bambino, abbia ucciso questi individui.
And how He made them out though they were all camouflaged.
E come li abbia smascherati nonostante fossero tutti camuffati.
n these modern times, difficult for people to believe
Al giorno d’oggi si stenta a credere
that there could have been any incarnation like Shri Krishna.
a credere che sia potuta esistere una incarnazione come Shri Krishna.
But in Sahaja Yoga, we have method of absolutely establishing the truth
Ma in Sahaja Yoga noi abbiamo il metodo per stabilire nel modo più assoluto la verità
that Shri Krishna was there ruling on the Vishuddhi chakra.
che Shri Krishna governava il Vishuddhi chakra.
From His childhood, you can see He was fond of collectivity.
Potete vedere come, fin dall’infanzia, amasse la collettività.
And He tried to create collectivity of people
E cercò di creare una collettività di gente
who were very simple, uneducated, good-hearted people.
molto semplice, non istruita, ma di buon cuore.
And that is His special quality.
E questa è la Sua qualità speciale.
And all the people of that village knew Him very well, all cared for Him.
E tutti gli abitanti di quel villaggio
And when He had to go,
E quando dovette partire
they felt very sad and all of them came running and crying for Him.
si sentirono molto tristi e accorsero tutti piangendo per Lui.
It was a small boy who was going.
In fondo era un ragazzino che partiva:
After all, what is there? A little boy from the village is going.
cosa c’è di straordinario nella partenza di un ragazzino da un villaggio?
The whole village had gathered to cry for Him.
(Ma) tutto il villaggio si era riunito a piangere per Lui.
That is what we all Sahaja Yogis have to know.
Questo è ciò che tutti noi sahaja yogi dobbiamo sapere.
As a child also, He was a very collective personality.
Anche da bambino Egli era una personalità molto collettiva.
He actually emits collectiveness.
In effetti emana collettività.
The collective consciousness that you enjoy is because of His bliss.
La consapevolezza collettiva di cui gioite è frutto della Sua benedizione.
I find that Americans are very collective in the sense,
Io trovo che gli americani siano molto collettivi, nel senso
they are more bothered about other countries than about their own.
che sono più preoccupati degli altri paesi che del loro.
They want to go all the way to Vietnam, now to Iraq, now to some other place.
Vogliono andare fino in Vietnam, adesso in Iraq, ora in qualche altro paese.
Going all over the world, they try to correct.
Vanno in tutto il mondo a cercare di correggerlo.
But their own country they do not see what's wrong. It's so divided.
Ma non vedono ciò che non va nel proprio paese. È molto diviso:
Mainly divided on race, racial discrimination,
diviso soprattutto in base alle razze, a causa della discriminazione razziale,
is divided by religions and all of these are just concepts
è diviso in base alle religioni. Tutti questi sono solo concetti
which they have accepted and are fighting among themselves.
che loro hanno accettato, e lottano tra loro.
Now after all these,
Ora, oltre a tutto questo,
there are people who believe they are born criminals and they should be criminals.
ci sono individui che credono di essere nati criminali e di dover essere criminali.
And their criminality is going very far.
E la loro criminalità si sta spingendo troppo in là.
They are gangsters. Even small children have become gangsters.
Sono gangster. Persino dei bambini piccoli sono diventati gangster.
But the worst part is that the, these little boys also,
Ma l’aspetto peggiore è che anche questi ragazzini,
including others, all these criminals are regarded as big heroes.
oltre agli altri, a tutti questi criminali, sono considerati grandi eroi.
I have seen once, a young boy wearing a shirt
Una volta ho visto un ragazzino che indossava una maglietta
with another young boy’s photograph over it.
con sopra la fotografia di un altro ragazzino.
So he told Me - I said, “Who is this?” “You don’t know?
E mi disse… io gli chiesi chi fosse e lui rispose: “Non lo conosce?
Very famous gangster is he”, he said.
È un gangster famosissimo”.
At the age of thirteen years he is a very famous gangster
A tredici anni è un gangster molto famoso
and this boy is very proudly putting up that -
e questo ragazzo è molto fiero di mettersi questa maglietta,
like a big hero, or you can call it like a God there.
come se costui fosse un grande eroe o, diciamo, una divinità.
So see the perversion to what limit Shri Krishna's blessings have been used.
Notate la perversione, fino a che limite
That's why this country is very difficult.
Ecco perché questo paese è molto difficile.
One after another there has been attack of negativity.
Ci sono stati attacchi di negatività uno dietro l’altro.
For example, first thing started by Christians,
Il primo, ad esempio, iniziò con i cristiani
who said that Jews killed Christ.
i quali accusarono gli ebrei di aver ucciso Cristo.
He never - It’s not true, it’s not true. He was never killed by Jews.
Non è vero, non è vero. Lui non è stato ucciso dagli ebrei.
“Christ was killed by Jews”, is a false statement, absolutely.
Che Cristo sia stato ucciso dagli ebrei è un’asserzione falsa, assolutamente.
Christ was not killed by Jews. How can a multitude kill a man?
Cristo non fu ucciso dagli ebrei. Come può una moltitudine uccidere un uomo?
It’s the law there. The Romans, or we can call the Roman law crucified Him.
È la legge a farlo. Furono i romani, o meglio, la legge romana a crocifiggerlo.
So the Christians started nicely torturing the Jews, because Christ was killed.
Così i cristiani iniziarono a tormentare ben bene gli ebrei
I don’t know how to explain this such absurd idea.
Non so come spiegare un’idea così assurda.
Now somebody was killed so many years back, and now what’s the use of killing
Qualcuno è stato ucciso tanto tempo addietro e, adesso, a che serve uccidere
some grandchildren of those people or great grandchildren of those people?
i nipoti o i pronipoti di quella gente?
But they did not, the Jews did not.
Ma non lo fecero loro, non furono gli ebrei a farlo.
Still this concept was there that the Jews killed.
Tuttavia sussisteva questa idea secondo la quale lo avevano ucciso gli ebrei,
And the Christians felt they have a right to torture the Jews.
e i cristiani si sentirono in diritto di tormentarli.
So when the Jews came here, they were never given a good position,
Pertanto, quando gli ebrei arrivarono qui,
they were tortured very much and troubled very much.
furono tormentati ed angariati a dismisura.
It happened everywhere but very much more here.
È accaduto ovunque ma molto di più qui.
So among Jews now came out some devils, like Freud.
Così, fra gli ebrei spuntarono alcuni demoni come Freud,
And he said, “All right. We must shatter these Christians absolutely.
il quale disse: “Bene. Dobbiamo distruggere completamente questi cristiani.
Their moral roots must be finished.”
Le loro radici morali devono essere distrutte”.
So he started his own psychology to destroy the Christians.
Pertanto iniziò la sua psicologia al fine di distruggere i cristiani.
And Christians stupidly accepted.
E i cristiani l’hanno accettata stupidamente.
They did whatever he said,
Hanno fatto tutto ciò che lui ha detto,
experimented whatever he did.
hanno sperimentato tutto ciò che lui ha fatto.
When I was once in Switzerland, two girls came and they were shaking in the program.
Una volta ero in Svizzera ed arrivarono al programma due ragazze che tremavano.
I couldn't understand. I called them. I said, "Why are you shaking?"
Non riuscivo a capire. Le chiamai e chiesi perché tremassero.
So they said that, "Actually we are very much degree holders in Freudian knowledge
Loro risposero: “In effetti siamo esperte laureate in scienze freudiane
and we have done all experiments of Freud."
e abbiamo sperimentato tutte le teorie di Freud”.
“And then why are you shaking?” “Because we have power to shake!” How about that?
“E allora perché tremate?”. “Perché abbiamo il potere di tremare!”. Pensate un po’.
So they followed this Freud and this vindictiveness that was there
Loro seguivano questo Freud e questo sentimento vendicativo insito
was not seen by anyone, even by Jews.
non era stato percepito da nessuno, neppure dagli ebrei.
As a result we had people who were deadly against each other
Di conseguenza ci sono state persone che si avversavano implacabilmente
and ruining each other, destroying each other.
e si rovinavano e si distruggevano a vicenda.
Then this Black and White business started.
Poi ebbe inizio questa faccenda dei bianchi e dei neri.
All kinds of theories people are putting up
La gente tira fuori teorie di ogni genere
to show that the Blacks are bad or the Whites are bad.
per dimostrare che i neri sono cattivi o che i bianchi sono cattivi.
The difference is only skin-deep.
La differenza è solo epidermica.
If you want you can cut the skin and see for yourself.
Se volete potete tagliare la pelle e vedere voi stessi.
Inside body is the same. But it was so.
All’interno il corpo è uguale. Ma è accaduto questo,
This divisive method started and it's still going on.
è iniziato questo metodo che crea divisione e ciò continua tuttora.
I always say, without Blacks, Americans will be left high and dry.
Io dico sempre che senza i neri gli americani si troverebbero persi.
Look at the talent they have.
Guardate quanto talento hanno,
Not only music. Atlanta, I saw,
non solo per la musica. Ad Atlanta ho visto
all the Blacks were winning and Whites were not anywhere. Just imagine.
che i vincitori erano tutti neri e i bianchi non erano da nessuna parte.
And all the Whites were saying, "Ha, ha, ha."
Tutti i bianchi facevano “Ha, ha, ha” (per la fatica, ndt),
They were nicely enjoying their position.
(mentre) loro si godevano soddisfatti i loro piazzamenti.
You don't have the stamina of the Blacks also.
Voi non avete neppure la resistenza dei neri.
So in games also, same thing.
Anche nei giochi è la stessa cosa.
With all this what is going to happen to America?
Con tutto questo, che cosa accadrà all’America?
It's a country which has to be collective because of Shri Krishna.
È un paese che deve essere collettivo a causa di Shri Krishna.
All of them are immigrants here. Who is not an immigrant?
Qui sono tutti immigrati. Chi non è un immigrato?
Whether they came earlier or later doesn't matter.
Che siano arrivati prima o dopo non ha importanza.
Thank God, I have told you many-a-times that Columbus lost his way
Vi ho detto molte volte che, grazie a Dio, Colombo sbagliò rotta
and came here, not to India. Otherwise, there would have been no Indians left
ed arrivò qui, non in India. Altrimenti non sarebbe rimasto nessun indiano
and no Sahaja Yoga.
e non sarebbe esistito neppure Sahaja Yoga.
I think, it was the trick of Hanumana.
Penso sia stato il trucco di Hanumana.
He misled him and Columbus came here. Thank God.
fu lui a sviarlo e Colombo è arrivato qui. Grazie a Dio.
Now, you are in a country where you have to be collective.
Voi dunque siete in un paese nel quale dovete essere collettivi.
Krishna won't spare you unless and until you are collective
Krishna non vi risparmierà se non sarete collettivi o se non la smetterete
or you give up this nonsense of skin-deep differences.
con questa assurdità delle differenze basate sul colore della pelle.
Then religious differences. He had a friend who was lame by one leg.
E poi le differenze religiose.
He had some friends who were very black.
Aveva amici che erano nerissimi.
He had some friends who were quite Indian white, I should say.
Aveva amici che erano degli indiani di pelle bianca, direi -
I shouldn’t say white like you people, but Indian white.
non direi bianchi come voi, ma indiani bianchi - ne ha avuto tutti i colori.
And He took His own birth in the Yadav vansha.
Ed Egli nacque nella dinastia Yadav,
Though they were milk sellers, milkmen who used to sell milk to people.
nonostante fossero commercianti di latte, lattai che vendevano il latte.
He didn't take His birth in a very royal family like Shri Rama.
Egli non nacque in una famiglia reale come Shri Rama,
Though He was, because later on He became the king of Dwarika.
sebbene lo fosse, infatti successivamente divenne re di Dwarika.
But in His style, in His behavior, in His life,
Ma dal Suo stile, dal Suo comportamento, dalla Sua vita
nobody could see that He was a royal personality.
nessuno poteva pensare che fosse una personalità regale.
He could sleep under a tree.
Egli poteva dormire sotto un albero.
He could eat anything that He could get.
Poteva mangiare qualunque cosa potesse ricevere.
All kinds of sweet, sweet stories you can read in His life,
Sulla Sua vita potete leggere tutte storie dolcissime
showing how He was enjoying His collectivity, never showing off.
che mostrano come gioisse della Sua collettività senza mai esibirsi.
And His collectivity has to be worked out in this country.
E la Sua collettività deve essere fatta funzionare in questo paese.
Unless and until it is done from your heart, it's not going to work out.
(Ma) se non sarà fatto con il cuore, non funzionerà.
We had problems like this always with our collectivity here.
Qui abbiamo sempre avuto problemi di questo genere, con la nostra collettività.
For example, a lady, you know, she is a big lady, I think.
Per esempio una signora - sapete, penso sia una signora “importante” -
She started correcting people: “Why do you put here?
si mise a correggere la gente: “Perché hai messo qui questa cosa?
This thing is getting dirty. That thing is this and that.”
Si sta sporcando. Questo è così e cosà”.
Such a woman should be sometimes sent to some stable to clean it.
Una donna del genere dovrebbe essere mandata una volta o l’altra a pulire una stalla:
Then she will give up these nonsensical ideas that she has.
allora la smetterà con queste sue idee assurde.
If you are a Sahaja Yogi you cannot behave like this.
Se siete sahaja yogi non potete comportarvi così.
And this kind of behavior can destroy Sahaja Yoga.
E questo genere di comportamento può distruggere Sahaja Yoga.
Have you ever heard Me saying that, “This is dirty,
Mi avete mai forse sentito dire: “Questo è sporco,
this is not good, I don’t like this?”. Did I say, ever?
questo non va bene, questo non mi piace?”. L’ho mai detto forse?
First of all, we have to understand, if we have to be collective,
Per prima cosa occorre comprendere che, se dobbiamo essere collettivi,
we should give up these stupid ideas about ourselves.
dovremmo eliminare queste stupide idee su noi stessi.
Some people get some position, may be some money,
Alcuni hanno qualche posizione, magari del denaro
maybe, I would say, have a background.
o magari, diciamo, una certa provenienza;
If you are sticking on to it then you are not a Sahaja Yogi.
(ma) se vi ci attaccate non siete sahaja yogi.
You are saints!
Voi siete santi!
You cannot be demanding.
Non potete essere pretenziosi.
You have to give, and give, and give.
Dovete dare e dare e dare.
Whatever may be your position in life,
Qualunque possa essere la vostra posizione nella vita,
if that can overpower you then you are not a Sahaja Yogi at all.
se essa può dominarvi non siete affatto sahaja yogi.
Shri Krishna, who is the Virat, who is the great primordial personality,
Shri Krishna, che è il Virata, che è la grandiosa personalità primordiale,
didn't show any such signs of His greatness.
non ha fatto mai mostra della Sua grandezza.
But Americans have a speciality to show
Ma gli americani hanno la specialità di mostrarsi
that they are something outstandingly great.
come qualcosa di eccezionalmente grande.
But Sahaja Yogis, please don't learn those things.
Però, voi sahaja yogi, per favore, non imparate queste cose.
You have to make others unlearn.
Voi dovete farle disimparare agli altri.
If that cannot happen, it's better to leave Sahaja Yoga for ever.
Se ciò non accade, è meglio lasciare per sempre Sahaja Yoga.
Such people will make everyone miserable and destroy Sahaja Yoga in America.
Gente simile renderà tutti infelici e distruggerà Sahaja Yoga in America.
Even about protocol, you should become timeless.
Anche per quanto riguardo il protocollo, dovreste diventare senza tempo,
Absolutely timeless.
assolutamente oltre il tempo.
Now, if you are particular about time, Shri Krishna will play His tricks
Se siete puntigliosi riguardo al tempo, Shri Krishna metterà in atto i Suoi trucchi
and your timing will be finished. Happened yesterday.
e la vostra minuziosità per il tempo fallirà. È accaduto ieri.
So, one has to know that time is your slave
Quindi si deve capire che il tempo è vostro schiavo
and you don't have to be the slave of time - if you are a Sahaja Yogi.
e non dovete essere voi schiavi del tempo, se siete sahaja yogi.
Otherwise, you are not. That means you are guided not by the Divine.
Diversamente non lo siete. Questo significa che non siete guidati dal Divino.
The Divine works out everything very well. But for whom? For Sahaja Yogis.
Il Divino fa funzionare tutto molto bene, ma per chi? Per i sahaja yogi.
But if you are not Sahaja Yogis, you'll topple down.
Se però non siete sahaja yogi, cadrete giù.
In every way we should find out what things we have accumulated among ourselves
Dovremmo scoprire, in qualsiasi modo, quali cose abbiamo accumulato tra noi
which is not Shri Krishna's quality.
che non sono qualità di Shri Krishna.
Now, Shri Krishna used to steal as a child, the butter from the ladies, why?
Ora, Shri Krishna da bambino rubava il burro alle donne.
to the military of Kamsa, His uncle, who was a devil.
all’esercito di Kamsa, Suo zio, il quale era un demone.
They used to go all the way to sell him in Mathura.
Si recavano fino a Mathura per venderglielo.
So He used to steal it, because children needed it, and giving it to children.
Così Lui lo rubava e lo dava ai bambini perché essi ne avevano bisogno.
He didn’t like this idea – why should it go
Non gli piaceva l’idea che dovesse andare
to these horrible rakshasas of Mathura.
a quegli orribili rakshasa di Mathura.
Just the opposite in is America.
In America è l’esatto contrario:
All the false gurus, all the rakshasas come here and they get all the butter.
tutti i falsi guru, tutti i rakshasa arrivano qui e ricevono tutto il burro.
As if people have no brains to understand,
Come se la gente non avesse cervello per capire;
while Shri Krishna is the brain of the Virat.
mentre Shri Krishna è il cervello del Virata.
But here you find that people have no brains.
Ma qui si scopre che la gente è senza cervello.
Anybody comes, says something, they: “Ah, ha, ha, great.”
Chiunque arrivi e affermi qualcosa, la gente (dirà): “Ha, ah, ah, straordinario”.
Somebody talks big - all right.
Se qualcuno fa grandi discorsi, bene,
They’ll give away their money. They’ll give away their houses.
gli regaleranno il proprio denaro, gli regaleranno le proprie case,
Their children they’ll remove from the school – for something extremely stupid.
ritireranno i figli da scuola, per qualcosa di estremamente stupido.
While He is the brain in the body of Virata.
Mentre Egli è il cervello nel corpo del Virata.
So this kind of brainlessness comes
Si crea dunque questo genere di scervellatezza
and we really start, even Sahaja Yogis start behaving in a manner
per cui si inizia realmente – anche i sahaja yogi - a comportarsi in un modo
that shows they are really brainless.
che dimostra che sono davvero senza cervello.
Apart from that, He is Kubera. He is the God of wealth.
Oltre a questo, Lui è Kubera. È il Dio della ricchezza.
That's why there is wealth in this country.
Ecco perché in questo paese c’è ricchezza.
But this wealth is all becoming debts, you see,
Ma questa ricchezza si sta trasformando tutta in debiti, sapete,
because of the special brains of Americans.
a causa del cervello speciale degli americani.
They are so stupid that whatever is selling in the market,
Loro sono così stupidi che qualsiasi cosa sia in vendita
whether they need it or not, they'll buy.
la compreranno, che ne abbiano bisogno o no.
Take loan, again take loan, take loan
Chiedono un prestito, poi un altro, poi un altro,
till they are absolutely indebted.
finché non finiscono completamente indebitati.
Now here in the country of Kubera you should be really rich.
Ora qui, nel paese di Kubera, dovreste essere davvero ricchi.
Rich doesn't mean just to have bank balance, but means by temperament.
Ricchezza non significa soltanto avere un conto in banca, ma indica il temperamento.
Now it's much better but once upon a time,
Adesso va molto meglio, ma una volta
Americans were the most miserly Sahaja Yogis.
gli americani erano i sahaja yogi più avari.
They used to send Me candles as present and I used to hide that.
Mi mandavano in regalo delle candele, ed io le nascondevo.
I said, "Baba why do you send candles, even? Don't send anything,
Dicevo: “Santo cielo, perché mandate queste candele? Piuttosto non mandate nulla,
because everybody is going to see those candles
perché tutti vedranno queste candele,
and what are they going to say about it, that candles have been sent."
e cosa diranno del fatto che le avete mandate?”.
Now, this I am talking for introspection.
Ora, ne sto parlando perché facciate introspezione.
Are we collective? Are we willing to share everything that we have?
Siamo collettivi? Siamo disposti a condividere tutto ciò che abbiamo?
Do we look down upon people who come from other countries?
Guardiamo dall’alto in basso le persone provenienti da altri paesi?
Do we have racialism in us?
Alberga in noi del razzismo?
Thirty-five Sahaja Yogis came from Australia
Trentacinque sahaja yogi australiani arrivarono
to America as if this is some Hajj.
in America come se fosse un Hajj (pellegrinaggio alla Mecca, ndt).
They went back with very bad vibrations.
Tornarono con pessime vibrazioni.
Out of them half were thrown out of Sahaja Yoga.
Metà di loro fu espulsa da Sahaja Yoga.
Imagine, Australia is the country where they used to send all the criminals.
Pensate, l’Australia è il paese in cui solevano mandare tutti i criminali.
So first and foremost, to judge yourself is to see your vibrations.
Il modo principale per giudicare voi stessi è esaminare le vostre vibrazioni.
That you should meditate and judge your vibrations
Dovreste meditare e giudicare, in base alle vostre vibrazioni,
if you are really collective or not.
se siete davvero collettivi oppure no.
Because you are not like that, Sahaja Yoga does not spread.
Dato che non lo siete, Sahaja Yoga non si diffonde.
I have seen people from Hare Rama Hare Krishna.
Ho visto i seguaci degli Hare Rama Hare Krishna.
Poor things have found nothing. They get up at four o'clock,
Poveretti, non hanno trovato nulla. Si alzano alle quattro del mattino
start their Hare Rama Hare Krishna bhajan - four o'clock. Alright.
ed iniziano a cantare il loro bhajan Hare Rama Hare Krishna:
Then the whole day they wear a very thin dhoti in which they are shivering.
Poi per tutto il giorno indossano un dhoti molto leggero in cui tremano di freddo.
They shave their heads and put a very…
Si rasano la testa e si appiccicano un codino che si compra al mercato.
If you see their dedication you'll be surprised.
Se pensate alla loro dedizione vi sorprenderete.
How they are so much dedicated, when they haven't found anything whatsoever?
Come mai sono tanto dedicati nonostante non abbiano trovato assolutamente nulla?
What about the nuns? You see them, you’ll be amazed.
E le suore? Guardatele e sarete stupiti.
One fellow came from the Catholic Church to us.
È venuta da noi una persona della chiesa cattolica.
He was trying to be a priest. He said, “Mother, Sahaja Yog –
Stava cercando di diventare prete e disse: “Madre, in Sahaja Yoga
you don’t do anything, anything.” I said, “What do you want to do?”
voi non fate nulla”. Io chiesi: “Che cosa vuole fare?”.
“You know, there we could not eat any meat on Fridays.
“Sa, è che là non si poteva mangiare carne il venerdì.
On Saturdays, we could not drink anything.
Il sabato non potevamo bere niente.
Then on Sundays, the whole day we had to fast and pray to God."
La domenica poi dovevamo digiunare e pregare Dio per tutto il giorno”.
"Then - what about the rest of the time?"
“E poi, il resto del tempo?”.
"The rest of the time, we had to remember Bible by heart and then recite it.
“Il resto del tempo dovevamo imparare la Bibbia a memoria e poi recitarla.
And if we made even one mistake, the father would give us a nice beating.”
E se facevamo anche un solo errore, il “padre” (prete, ndt)
That's another problem with Sahaja Yoga because it is Shri Krishna's play.
È un altro problema con Sahaja Yoga, perché esso è il gioco di Shri Krishna.
It's so simple. You don't have to do anything of the kind.
È molto semplice. Voi non dovete fare nulla del genere.
No disciplining, nothing. Left to you, you are your own master.
Nessuna disciplina, niente. È lasciato a voi, voi siete il vostro maestro.
You are your own guru.
Siete il vostro guru.
But these things which are lingering in your mind,
Tuttavia, queste cose che perdurano nella vostra mente,
which are just the opposite of Shri Krishna’s life,
che sono proprio l’opposto della vita di Shri Krishna,
which you have acquired in this country,
che avete acquisito in questo paese, persistono tuttora qui e là, qua e là.
Some of the people are really still so much busy with themselves.
Alcune persone sono tuttora molto impegnate con se stesse.
They look so pale, thin – I tell you, I can’t believe they are Sahaja Yogis.
Sono così pallide, magre, vi assicuro che non posso credere siano sahaja yogi.
So when we see Shri Krishna's life, the way He lived.
Ebbene, quando osserviamo la vita di Shri Krishna, il modo in cui visse…
And then He went to help the Pandavas.
Andò anche in aiuto dei Pandava.
He told Arjuna that, "I can be your charioteer.
Disse ad Arjuna: “Io posso essere il tuo auriga,
I can drive your chariot. But I will not fight."
posso guidare il tuo carro, ma non combatterò”.
Arjuna knew that He was all-powerful, if He is there everything will work out.
Arjuna sapeva che Egli era onnipotente
“And all My army I’ll give to Kauravas, to seek the balance.”
“E darò ai Kaurava l’intero mio esercito, per cercare l’equilibrio”.
He said, "All right."
Egli rispose: “Va bene”.
He didn't fight to show off, I am this, I am that.
Ma Lui (Shri Krishna) non combatté, per non ostentare di essere questo o quello.
Like here: “Mother, I am the leader”. Eh?
Come qui: “Madre, io sono il leader”. Eh?!
“I am the leader.” “Can’t hear, I can’t hear you.”
“Io sono il leader”. “Non riesco a sentire, non riesco a sentirti”
"Mother, I am this."
“Madre, io sono questo”.
You are a Sahaja Yogi.
Voi siete sahaja yogi.
It's a very great name that you have achieved.
È un grandissimo titolo quello che avete acquisito.
The highest position you have achieved. There’s nothing more to be achieved.
Avete conseguito la posizione più elevata. Non c’è niente di più da raggiungere.
Like somebody asked Me, “Mother, the Indians in India never catch.
Qualcuno mi ha chiesto: “Madre, in India gli indiani non prendono mai blocchi.
Why do we go on catching all the time?” I said, “Because Indians in India
Perché noi invece prendiamo blocchi di continuo?”.
know they have achieved it now. Nothing to be achieved.
di averlo ormai acquisito. Non c’è niente (di più) da conseguire.
And you want to have God’s Realization – I don’t know what other Realization.”
Mentre voi (americani) volete avere la realizzazione di Dio,
They say, "We have achieved now. We are in the sea. It's for us to swim over."
Dicono: “Adesso l’abbiamo ottenuta. Siamo nel mare, dobbiamo nuotare”.
All these things some of you have crossed over, some of you
Tutte queste cose alcuni di voi le hanno superate, altri
have absolutely lost them. But some of you are still there.
le hanno perse completamente. Invece alcuni di voi ci sono ancora invischiati.
They are the most dangerous thing as Christ has said,
Costoro sono la cosa più pericolosa, come disse Cristo:
"Be careful of the murmuring souls."
“State attenti alle anime mormoranti”.
I don't know how to stop this little rat-like people,
Io non so come bloccare questa gentucola, simile a topi,
who are cutting the nest of Sahaja Yoga.
che sta demolendo il nido di Sahaja Yoga..
I've been reported about many and I am really shocked.
Mi è stato riferito di molti e ne sono davvero scioccata.
After so many years of My visit how can people talk ill of each other
Dopo tanti anni che vengo qui, come possono sparlare l’uno dell’altro
and can create these problems?
e creare questi problemi?
Shri Krishna's friendship is well known, you know with Sudama how He behaved.
Il senso di amicizia di Shri Krishna è ben noto; sapete come si comportò con Sudama.
All His beautiful manifestations must show in your character.
Tutte le Sue meravigliose manifestazioni devono evidenziarsi nel vostro carattere.
Then only this country can be saved.
Solo allora questo paese può essere salvato.
I must say it’s – now here we have Canada, we have people also,
Devo dire… adesso qui abbiamo il Canada, mi hanno detto che abbiamo gente anche
I am told from Austria. From all over, from England.
dall’Austria; da ogni parte; dall’Inghilterra.
But still, we are not so many people as we should have been.
Eppure non siamo tanti quanti dovremmo.
If you just take Austrians, they must be double of this.
Se prendiamo solo gli austriaci, devono essere il doppio di così.
If they could do it, why can't we do it?
Se hanno potuto farlo loro, perché non possiamo riuscirci noi?
Because we do not introspect and we do not grow out of our egos.
Perché non facciamo introspezione e non ci affranchiamo dal nostro ego.
They will say that, "Why didn't Krishna meditate?"
Diranno: “Perché Krishna non meditava?”.
You have to meditate on Shri Krishna.
Siete voi che dovete meditare su Shri Krishna.
If He meditates what will happen to you all?
Se medita Lui, che cosa accadrà a tutti voi?
On the whole, I was very happy with yesterday -
Nel complesso, in qualche modo, sono rimasta molto soddisfatta del programma
Despite that we had so many people and I put the responsibility on them.
Malgrado ciò, abbiamo avuto moltissime persone
And that is what is your responsibility now.
E questa è adesso la vostra responsabilità.
You are responsible for America and Canada, South America.
Voi siete responsabili dell’America, del Canada e del Sud America.
You all are responsible and you people should be such
Siete tutti responsabili e dovreste essere tali
that people who see you, listen to you, are with you,
che la gente, vedendovi, vi ascolti, sia con voi,
should know that these are the Gopa and Gopis of Shri Krishna.
sappia che siete i gopa e le gopi di Shri Krishna.
Unless and until that thing happens, this America is the most difficult place.
Finché ciò non accadrà, l’America sarà il luogo più difficile.
Sometimes I feel it's not Gokul but Mathura.
A volte ho la sensazione che non sia Gokul ma Mathura.
So it is for you - and otherwise you cannot enjoy.
Sta dunque a voi; diversamente non potrete gioire.
If you live with your all old clothes, you can't enjoy.
Se continuate a vivere con tutti i vostri vecchi vestiti, non potete gioire.
I must say this time there were so many people and I have asked them to promise,
Devo dire che questa volta ci sono state molte persone
I am sure. But it is you people who disappoint them.
Ne sono certa. Ma siete voi che li deludete.
When they see you, they are disappointed.
Quando vi vedono rimangono delusi.
Actually, here is the first time, Vishwa Nirmala Dharm
Per la verità qui Vishwa Nirmala Dharma è stato riconosciuto
has been established as a religion.
per la prima volta come religione.
It is. But the rest of it is zero.
È così. Ma per il resto è zero.
So all these differences and divisiveness has to finish
Pertanto, tutte queste differenze e divisioni devono finire
and we should be one in the collective nature of Shri Krishna.
e dovremmo essere uno nella natura collettiva di Shri Krishna.
First, meditation is very important. Introspection is very important.
Prima di tutto la meditazione è fondamentale.
And also, meeting each other, talking to each other,
Ed anche incontrarvi, parlare tra voi,
knowing each other is very important.
conoscervi è molto importante.
It has worked all over. It’s worked out in India tremendously,
Ha funzionato ovunque. Ha funzionato in modo straordinario in India,
Russia tremendously, Bulgaria tremendously, so why not here?
in Russia, in Bulgaria; perché non qui allora?
It's no fashion for brainless people.
Non è una moda per gente senza cervello.
It is a living process which has to take place where you must mature.
È un processo vivente che deve attuarsi e nel quale dovete maturare.
And what I find that Americans are not matured.
E ciò che trovo è che gli americani non sono maturi.
But you are now mature. You are now mature people.
Voi però adesso siete maturi. Ora voi siete persone mature
And I hope you will all behave like mature people henceforth.
e spero che, d’ora in avanti, vi comporterete tutti da persone mature.
So may God bless you!
Che Dio vi benedica.
(Aside to somebody) Can we have…?
(A lato a qualcuno) Possiamo avere…?
There are Shri Krishna's names they have written down
Sono stati trascritti i nomi di Shri Krishna
and I would request leaders to come on the stage.
e chiederei ai leader di venire sul palco.
Now try to understand every word, every name of Shri Krishna.
Adesso cercate di comprendere ogni parola, ogni nome di Shri Krishna.
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
(Aside to a yogi) Also, you say the name first, and then they will repeat it.
(A lato ad uno yogi) Inoltre, dì prima il nome e poi loro lo ripeteranno.
Name and the meaning, and then they will repeat it.
Il nome ed il significato, e poi loro lo ripeteranno.
You just move on.
Spostatevi avanti.
Yogi: Can we have the leaders of the centers please come up to the stage?
Yogi: I leader dei vari centri per favore possono salire sul palco?
Shri Mataji: But are the… we didn’t have the children’s thing.
Shri Mataji: Ma… non abbiamo avuto (il puja dei) bambini.
What about the children? Eh?
E i bambini? Eh?
We have here, they can also come.
Li abbiamo qui, possono venire anche loro.
Firstly let us do little bit of Ganesh - Ganesha Puja, then you’ll walk in.
Prima facciamo un breve puja a Ganesha, poi verrete voi.
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
If there are children. Eh? [Hindi]
Se ci sono bambini. Eh? [Hindi]
Very few children there are.
Ci sono pochissimi bambini.
Yogi: Can we please have the children up on the stage
Yogi: Possiamo per favore avere i bambini sul palco
to do Ganesha, Shri Ganesha puja.
per celebrare il puja a Ganesha, a Shri Ganesha?
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
Just a minute. Ganesha Mantra…
Solo un minuto. Mantra di Ganesha…
What is there? (Unclear) Too vital!
Che cosa c’è? Troppo vivaci!
Yogi: Take the mantra to Shri Ganesha. Shri Mataji: Ganesha mantra.
Yogi: Diciamo il mantra a Shri Ganesha. Shri Mataji: Ganesha mantra.
Now. [Hindi]
Ora. [Hindi]
Just a minute, just a minute!
Un minuto, un minuto!
[Hindi]
[Hindi]
Shri Mataji: Sing song of Ganesha’s. Some Ganesha’s songs could we have.
Shri Mataji: Cantate un canto su Ganesha. Possiamo avere qualche canto su Ganesha?
Yogi: Ganesh Sthuti.
Yogi: Ganesh Sthuti.
Shri Mataji: [Hindi]
Shri Mataji: [Hindi]
Yogi: Sanskrit 11.
Yogi: Sanscrito 11.
Yogi: We’ll take the 108 Names of Shri Krishna.
Yogi: Reciteremo i centootto nomi di Shri Krishna.
First we’ll say the name in Sanskrit, then the meaning,
Prima diremo il nome in sanscrito, poi il significato
and then we’ll take the mantra.
e dopo reciteremo il mantra.
[Recitation of 108 Names of Shri Krishna begins. Not all of them are shown
[Ha inizio la recitazione dei 108 Nomi di Shri Krishna. Non tutti sono mostrati
on the video as in several parts the video gets interrupted.]
sul video poiché esso si interrompe in diversi punti, ndt]
2) Shridhar: He who has Shri Shakti.
2) Shridhar: Ha Shri Shakti.
4) Shriman: He who holds all the wealth.
4) Shriman: Possiede ogni ricchezza.
5) Nirmalagamya: He who is accessibile only through Shri Mataji.
5) Nirmalagamya: È accessibile soltanto grazie a Shri Mataji.
6) Shri Nirmala Pujak: He who worships Shri Mataji.
6) Shri Nirmala Pujak: Venera Shri Mataji.
7) Nirmal Bhakta Priya: He who loves the devotees of Shri Mataji.
7) Nirmal Bhakta Priya: Ama i devoti di Shri Mataji.
8) Nirmal Hriday: He who has the Lotus Feet of Shri Mataji in His heart.
8) Nirmal Hriday: Custodisce nel Suo cuore i piedi di loto di Shri Mataji.
9) Shri Niradhar: He who needs no support.
9) Shri Niradhar: Non gli occorre alcun sostegno.
10) Shri Vishwadhar Janak: He is the Father of Christ.
10) Shri Vishwadhar Janak: È il Padre di Cristo.
11) Shri Vishnu: He who is Shri Vishnu.
11) Shri Vishnu: È Shri Vishnu.
13) Shri Vishnumaya Sughoshita: He is announced by Shri Vishnumaya.
13) Shri Vishnumaya Sughoshita: È annunciato da Shri Vishnumaya.
15) Shri Vageshwari Bhrata: He is the brother of Maha Saraswati.
15) Shri Vageshwari Bhrata: È il fratello di Maha Saraswati.
17) Shri Draupadi Bandhu: He is the brother of Draupadi.
17) Shri Draupadi Bandhu: È il fratello di Draupadi.
18) Shri Partha Sakha: He is the friend to Arjuna.
18) Shri Partha Sakha: È l’amico di Arjuna.
19) Shri Sanmitra: He is the true friend.
19) Shri Sanmitra: È il vero amico.
20) Vishwa Vyapi: He permeates the universe.
20) Vishwa Vyapi: Permea l’universo.
21) Shri Vishwa Rakshi: He guards
21) Shri Vishwa Rakshi: Sorveglia l’Universo.
22) Shri Vishwa Sakshi: He witnesses the cosmic play.
22) Shri Vishwa Sakshi: È il testimone del gioco cosmico.
23) Shri Dwarakadhisha: He rules over Dwaraka.
23) Shri Dwarakadhisha: Governa Dwaraka.
24) Vishuddhi Prantadhisha: He rules over the country of Vishuddhi.
24) Vishuddhi Prantadhisha: Governa il paese del Vishuddhi.
25) Shri Jana Nayak: He leads the people.
25) Shri Jana Nayak: Guida i popoli.
26) Shri Vishuddhi Jana Palaka: He protects the people of the land of Vishuddhi.
26) Shri Vishuddhi Jana Palaka: Protegge il popolo della terra del Vishuddhi.
32) Shri Subhasha: He who has perfect speech.
32) Shri Subhasha: Ha un linguaggio perfetto.
34) Shri Sunasik: He has a perfect nose.
34) Shri Sunasik: Ha un naso
35) Shri Sudanta: He has perfect teeth.
35) Shri Sudanta: Ha denti perfetti.
36) Shri Sukesha: He who has perfect hair.
36) Shri Sukesha: Ha capelli perfetti.
39) Shri Sudarshan Dhari: He uses the Sudarshan to protect the seekers.
39) Shri Sudarshan Dhari: Usa il Sudarshan per proteggere i ricercatori.
42) Shri Rana Pandit: He is the Master of the art of warfare.
42) Shri Rana Pandit: È il maestro dell’arte bellica.
43) Shri Rana Chod: He runs away from the battlefield to win the war.
43) Shri Rana Chod: Fugge dal campo di battaglia per vincere la guerra.
44) Shrinath: He is the Master of Paramchaitanya.
44) Shrinath: È il maestro del Paramchaitanya.
46) Shri Akbar: He is the greatest person.
46) Shri Akbar: È il più grande.
47) Shri Akhileshwar: He is the God of the whole universe.
47) Shri Akhileshwar: È il Dio dell’Universo intero.
48) Shri Maha Virata: He is the Great Being of which everything else is part and parcel.
48) Shri Maha Virata: È il Grande Essere di cui ogni altra cosa è parte integrante.
49) Shri Yogeshwara: He is the God of the yogis.
49) Shri Yogeshwara: È il Dio degli yogi.
51) Shri Yogavarnitha: He describes Yoga as the destination.
51) Shri Yogavarnitha: Indica lo Yoga come fine ultimo.
53) Shri Vishwa Dharma Dhwaja Dharaka: He upholds the flag of Vishwa Dharma.
53) Shri Vishwa Dharma Dhwaja Dharaka: Tiene alta l’insegna di Vishwa Dharma.
54) Shri Garudarudha: He who rides on Garuda.
54) Shri Garudarudha: Cavalca Garuda.
Shri Mataji: Just like the bangles, put it like the bangles.
Shri Mataji: Proprio come i braccialetti, metteteli come i braccialetti.
57) Shri Padmadhara: He who holds the lotus.
57) Shri Padmadhara: Tiene in mano il loto.
60) Shri Govardhan Dhari: He lifted Govardhan mountain to protect the Gopas.
60) Shri Govardhan Dhari: Sollevò il monte Govardhan per dare riparo ai Gopa.
64) Shri Priya Bhashi: He whose speech is pleasing to the Spirit.
64) Shri Priya Bhashi: Il Suo linguaggio è gradito allo Spirito.
65) Shri Abhaya Pradayaka: He creates fearlessness.
65) Shri Abhaya Pradayaka: Infonde coraggio.
67) Shri Sadhak Rakshaka: He protects the seekers of truth.
67) Shri Sadhak Rakshaka: Protegge i ricercatori della Verità.
68) Shri Bhakta Vatsala: He loves devotees.
68) Shri Bhakta Vatsala: Ama i Suoi devoti.
69) Shri Shoka Hari: He destroys grief.
69) Shri Shoka Hari: Annienta il dolore.
70) Shri Dukha Nashak: He destroys sorrow.
70) Shri Dukha Nashak: Dissipa la tristezza.
71) Shri Rakshasa Hantri: He is the Killer of rakshasas.
71) Shri Rakshasa Hantri: È il distruttore dei rakshasa.
72) Shri Kurukula Virodhaka: He opposed the Kuru family which upheld a-dharma.
72) Shri Kurukula Virodhaka: Si oppose alla famiglia dei Kuru che sosteneva l’a-dharma.
73) Shri Gokul Vasi: He resides in Gokula.
73) Shri Gokul Vasi: Risiede a Gokul.
75) Shri Govind: He who enjoys cows.
75) Shri Govind: Ama le mucche.
76) Shri Yadu Kul Shreshtha: He is the highest of the Yadavas.
76) Shri Yadu Kul Shreshtha: È il più elevato degli Yadava.
77) Shri Akul: He who is beyond family attachments.
77) Shri Akul: Trascende gli attaccamenti familiari.
78) Shri Vansha Dwesha Nashaka:
78) Shri Vansha Dwesha Nashaka:
He is the destroyer of disparities according to caste, creed and race.
È il distruttore delle differenze di casta, credo e razza.
79) Shri Atma Gnyana Varnita:
79) Shri Atma Gnyana Varnita:
He who describes the knowledge of the Spirit.
Spiega la conoscenza dello Spirito.
80) Shri Agnyana Pranashaka:
80) Shri Agnyana Pranashaka:
He who describes how to destroy ignorance and non-knowledge.
Insegna come distruggere l’ignoranza e la falsa conoscenza.
81) Shri Nirakar: He who is beyond form. He is formless.
81) Shri Nirakar: È oltre la forma. È senza forma.
82) Shri Ananda-kar: He who is the joy personified.
82) Shri Ananda-kar: È la personificazione della gioia.
85) Shri Pavitra Rakshak: He protects the chastity.
85) Shri Pavitra Rakshak: Protettore della castità.
86) Shri Gnyananand: He has all of the pure knowledge of joy.
86) Shri Gnyananand: Possiede tutta la pura conoscenza della gioia.
88) Shri Gruhananda: He gives the joy of the household.
88) Shri Gruhananda: Dona la gioia della vita familiare.
89) Shri Dhanananda: He who gives the joy from prosperity.
89) Shri Dhanananda: Dona la gioia che deriva dalla prosperità.
90) Shri Kubera: He is the God of wealth and prosperità.
90) Shri Kubera: È il Dio della ricchezza e della prosperità.
91) Shri Atmananda: He gives the joy of the Spirit of God Almighty.
91) Shri Atmananda: Dona la gioia dello Spirito di Dio Onnipotente.
92) Shri Samukhananda: He gives the joy of the Sahaja collectivity.
92) Shri Samukhananda: Dona la gioia proveniente dalla collettività Sahaja.
94) Shri Vishuddhananda: He who gives pure joy.
94) Shri Vishuddhananda: Dona la gioia pura.
95) Shri Sangitananda: He gives the joy of music.
95) Shri Sangitananda: Dona la gioia della musica.
96) Shri Nrutyananda: He gives the joy of collective dancing.
96) Shri Nrutyananda: Dona la gioia della danza collettiva.
99) Shri Sahajananda: He gives joy through Sahaja culture.
99) Shri Sahajananda: Dona gioia mediante la cultura Sahaja.
100) Shri Paramananda: He gives absolute joy.
100) Shri Paramananda: Dona gioia assoluta.
102) Shri Natya Priya: He enjoys the play.
102) Shri Natya Priya: Ama il gioco.
104) Shri Kshir Priya: He who enjoys milk.
104) Shri Kshir Priya: Ama il latte.
105) Shri Dadhi Priya: He who enjoys curds.
105) Shri Dadhi Priya: Ama lo yogurt.
106) Shri Madhu Priya: He who enjoys honey.
106) Shri Madhu Priya: Ama il miele.
107) Shri Ghrut Priya: He who enjoys ghee.
107) Shri Ghrut Priya: Ama il ghee.
108) Shri Matru Charanamruta Priya:
108) Shri Matru Charanamruta Priya:
He who adores the amrut from the Holy Lotus Feet of Shri Mataji.
Adora l’amrut proveniente dai Sacri Piedi di Loto di Shri Mataji.
[Shri Mataji talks to an Indian yogini on stage who then says: “Vishwa vandita”]
[Shri Mataji parla ad una yogini indiana sul palco che poi riferisce: “Vishwa vandita”]
Yogi: Hindi 64.
Yogi: Hindi 64.
Yogi: Now we’ll all take a prayer as the expression of our pure desire.
Yogi: Adesso preghiamo tutti come espressione del nostro puro desiderio.
We’ll say together: Shri Mataji, we, all the sahaja yogis of the world,
Diremo insieme: Shri Mataji, tutti noi sahaja yogi del mondo
desire and pray for You to receive the Nobel Peace Prize.
desideriamo e preghiamo che Lei riceva il Premio Nobel per la Pace.
Let’s say it three times:
Diciamolo tre volte:
All yogis: Shri Mataji, we, all the sahaja yogis of the world,
Tutti gli yogi: Shri Mataji, tutti noi sahaja yogi del mondo
desire and pray for You to receive the Nobel Peace Prize.
desideriamo e preghiamo che Lei riceva il Premio Nobel per la Pace.
Shri Mataji, we, all the sahaja yogis of the world,
Shri Mataji, tutti noi sahaja yogi del mondo
desire and pray for You to receive the Nobel Peace Prize.
desideriamo e preghiamo che Lei riceva il Premio Nobel per la Pace.
Shri Mataji, we, all the sahaja yogis of the world,
Shri Mataji, tutti noi sahaja yogi del mondo
desire and pray for You to receive the Nobel Peace Prize.
desideriamo e preghiamo che Lei riceva il Premio Nobel per la Pace.
Shri Mataji: May God bless you. May God bless you.
Shri Mataji: Dio vi benedica. Dio vi benedica.
Yogi: Bolo Jagan Mata Shri Nirmala Devi Ki! Yogis: Jai!
Yogi: Bolo Jagan Mata Shri Nirmala Devi Ki! Gli yogi: Jai!
Shri Mataji: May God bless you all. May God bless you.
Shri Mataji: Dio vi benedica tutti. Dio vi benedica.
(Indistinct words – maybe Hindi)
(Parole indistinte – forse hindi)
(A lady on the stage bows to Shri Mataji, maybe a new leader)
(Una signora sul palco si inchina a Shri Mataji, forse una nuova leader)
Shri Mataji: I am sure she’ll establish the collectivity
Shri Mataji: Sono sicura che lei stabilizzerà molto bene la collettività
of the East Coast very well, and all of you should help.
della Costa Orientale e tutti voi dovreste aiutare.
Anybody who now tries to be mischievous about it
A chiunque adesso tenterà di fare dispetti al riguardo
we’ll have to ask you to get out, I’m sorry to say,
dovremo chiedere di andarsene, mi spiace dirlo,
we cannot disturb our collectivity any more. Alright? Thank you.
(ma) non possiamo più disturbare la nostra collettività. D’accordo? Grazie.
Lady on stage: Shri Mataji,
Signora sul palco: Shri Mataji,
we in America are so happy that You graced us with Your presence.
in America siamo molto felici che Lei ci abbia onorato della Sua presenza.
And part of letting people know who You are and why You are here,
E una azione per far conoscere alla gente chi è Lei e perché è qui,
is letting our governments know,
è informarne i nostri governi
so that they can have an opportunity to acknowledge Your greatness.
affinché possano avere l’opportunità di riconoscere la Sua grandezza.
So, Shri Mataji, I have this day two proclamations:
Pertanto, Shri Mataji, oggi ho due proclamazioni:
one from the city of Yonkers’ Mayor, who wants – yes.
una del Sindaco della città di Yonkers, il quale vuole… sì.
Ok. It comes from the office of the Mayor – city of Yonkers –
Ok. Viene dall’ufficio del Sindaco della città di Yonkers
and it’s proclamation which says – loudly –
e proclama – (dice a lato a qualcuno): a voce alta -
“Whereas the city of Yonkers takes great pride in recognizing those contributions
“Considerato che la città di Yonkers, è molto orgogliosa
And whereas foremost among these individuals is Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi,
E considerato che, eminente fra queste personalità è Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi,
whose unique discovery of Sahaja Yoga
la cui scoperta unica di Sahaja Yoga
has helped to bring understanding and peace to people in over 65 countries,
ha contribuito a portare comprensione e pace a persone in più di 65 Paesi,
where Her meditation techniques are practiced;
nei quali sono praticate le Sue tecniche di meditazione;
And whereas, Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi
E considerato che, Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi,
was born in 1923 in Chhindwara, India's center,
nata nel 1923 a Chindwara, nel centro dell’India,
and spent much of Her childhood in the ashram of Mahatma Gandhi,
trascorse gran parte della Sua infanzia nell’ashram del Mahatma Gandhi -
who because of Her great spiritual gifts consulted with Her frequently,
il quale La consultò spesso in virtù delle Sue (di Lei) grandi doti spirituali -
as a young woman, She played an active role in India's struggles for Independence
da giovane svolse un ruolo attivo nella lotta per l’indipendenza indiana
from British colonial rule. And after Independence was run,
dal dominio coloniale britannico. E dopo che l’indipendenza fu conquistata,
studied Medicine and Psychology, later marrying Sir C.P. Srivastava,
studiò medicina e psicologia, sposando in seguito Sir C.P. Shrivastava,
who served the Secretary General of the United Nations Maritime Organisation
che è stato Segretario Generale dell’Organizzazione Marittima